- Welcome, welcome, welcome.
I'm your host, Henry Arslanyan,
and welcome to this episode of the Future Money Podcast.
Before we start, I want to say a big thank you
to the half million of you who follow my content each week.
This podcast, The Future Money,
is now ranked in the top 5% of all podcasts
globally on Spotify.
Every week, thousands of you from over 160 countries
globally are tuning in.
So a massive thank you for all your support.
It really means a lot into an entire team
producing the Future Money Podcast.
As all of you loyal listeners know,
my goal with this podcast is very simple.
It's to go deep in some of the biggest ideas,
trends and developments we are seeing
in the field of crypto and hopefully empower you
with this information and then let you
make your own decision on what your impact
can be on the future of money and the future of finance.
And to do this, I invite each week one of the leading figures
of the global crypto community to have this one-on-one
conversation amongst crypto aficionados
and discuss some of these topics.
My guest today is Mr. Alessio Quaglini.
He's a CEO and co-founder of Hex Trust.
Before we jump right in, I have to say a couple things.
First of all, regular disclosures.
Personally, I am an investor in Hex Trust
and many previous or current sponsors or companies
I'm involved in are clients also of Hex Trust.
So we just want to put the disclosure out there
for transparency purposes.
Alessio, welcome to the show
and one thing for all your loyal listeners.
I mean, to show how dedicated Alessio is
to the crypto industry.
Today is his birthday and he's still decided
to come for this recording.
So Alessio, happy birthday and welcome
to the Future Money Podcast.
- Thank you so much, Henry.
My pleasure to be here and congrats
on the success of the podcast.
First of all, I know you're a big wine guy.
How are you going to celebrate your birthday today?
- I'm not sure it's going to be a surprise
but the expectations are quite high.
It's also my wife is a sommelier.
So let's see, let's see what she has prepared for me.
- Here we go, wife Sommelier
and you're a big wine aficionado.
So my God, that must be interesting on that perspective.
We have a lot of interesting show today.
I mean, I think for all the listeners on the show,
we've been really trying to,
there's been a lot of questions
on what is the future of custody, self custody
versus centralized custody?
What is going to be the future of staking services?
So I'll be in also some of the practical difficulties
of building a custodian
and whether custody services will become commoditized.
So we're going to try to discuss all these topics today.
Alessio, but before we jump right in,
do you mind maybe giving a bit of background on yourself
and also about Hex Trust?
And then we'll dive into the questions.
- Sure, firstly about myself, I'm Italian.
I've been in Hong Kong for the past 15 years.
By background, I'm an engineer,
but I didn't really spend too much time in my career
as a proper engineer
because I started working
the financial services industry early in my career.
Actually, funnily enough,
my first role in financial markets
was working for the regulator,
the securities regulator in Italy,
where I was responsible
of the supervision of intermediaries,
especially in the market manipulation
inside the trading, et cetera,
where we were bringing stochastic models
to understand the behaviors of investors
and trying to detect market anomalies.
After that, I joined the number of financial institutions
until the end of 2017,
when I met my co-founder, Rafael Serneski,
through a joint investment that we did
in one of the startups here in Hong Kong,
and we decided to do our own thing in the blockchain space,
and that's when X-Trust was born
at the beginning of 2018.
- Can you give a bit of summary on X-Trust
so we can get the audience
to understand what X-Trust is?
- Yeah, sure, so X-Trust was born,
as I was mentioning, at the beginning of 2018.
The idea was really to bring to the space
an institutional platform and institutional service
for custody of digital assets.
Why did we want to do it?
People tend to forget how different
the market was five years ago from what it is now.
It was mainly a retail space.
There were no rules and regulations.
There were a number of players
that were operating from offshore jurisdictions.
There was really little protection for investors
and hacks in terms of exchanges, et cetera,
and what were happening on a daily basis, right?
So we thought, okay, here we have a new asset class
first of all, which is gonna be very interesting
from sales side and buy side,
and at the same time, existing asset classes
might be ported to blockchain in the future.
So at a certain point,
institutional investors would be very interested
in entering the space, but to do that,
they will need that kind of institutional protection
and kind of set up that they are used to
in the traditional space.
That kind of set up that would avoid all those things
that we have experienced in the last few years
from happening in the space.
So we said, okay, let's try to bring this kind of offering
to the space and facilitate the entrance
of institutional investors.
We entered the space in 2018.
We really entered the market with the first offering
in the second half of 2019, but 2020
we're already quite established, especially in Asia.
We did a couple of rounds of very successful financing,
and as of today, we've basically become a global player
with offices in six jurisdictions.
So mainly we cover Asia, MENA, and Europe,
we're licensed in all the jurisdictions
where we have offices on Kong, Singapore, Dubai, Italy.
We just got a license in France and in the Bahamas.
And we started by offering the core service of custody,
and then we basically ventured into additional value
added services, such as on-ramp or framp,
staking, access to trading venues, et cetera.
- Let me focus on some of the things
you just mentioned, Alessio.
So, if you ask many people in the crypto community,
many people will tell you custody is becoming commoditized.
It's gonna be service people will just offer,
and it's very difficult to monetize custody.
Unless you have some of these additional services on top,
what do you think is the future of profitability
of crypto custodians?
I mean, do you think they will need to have these services
on top and slurry services,
or that it's gonna be custody by itself
is a business model that has a lot of future?
- All right, so there's a couple of points here, right?
So first of all, the commoditization of custody.
So it is true that custody is a commodity
in the traditional space,
but in the crypto space, we're far from it, in my opinion.
So the technology is evolving so fast.
We have new blockchain protocols,
we have new use cases, we have new business models,
and custody is really at the core
of facilitating and enabling these business models.
So whatever custodians were doing three years ago,
it is very different from what we are doing today.
So I would say that, yes, probably at a certain point
in the future, we'll have a more standard offering
of custody, but as of today,
from a technological perspective,
we're really far from having,
from custody being a commodity.
There's also a couple of aspects that are relevant
to the how custody is evolving in the blockchain space.
So the first one is, obviously that in the traditional space,
custody is basically a simple ledger
where you record who owns what, right?
And then you transfer, I mean, you synchronize this ledger
with the central depository institutions, et cetera.
So assets in the traditional space,
they're pure ledger entries.
And the blockchain space assets are basically smart contracts.
It means that they are programmable, they're live animals,
and some of the financial services
are already enabled within the asset.
So the asset is not a simple entry,
but it has already embedded in the asset itself
a number of services.
And these services, sometimes they don't require
an intermediary to enable them.
They require the custodian to make sure
that these assets can be useful for those services.
I'm talking, for example, about staking, right?
You don't need anymore an intermediary to enable staking,
right?
You can do it directly from your custodian
by signing a staking transaction on your assets,
because that staking transaction is part of the protocol
where the asset has been issued.
So there's a very important difference
from the traditional space,
and it has an impact on how commoditized the service is
and how you can monetize it.
Now, going to the monetization, yes,
obviously monetization is extremely complex,
and I would agree with you that it's much harder
to monetize a custody service
versus a trading service or an exchange service, et cetera.
However, the custody business brings
a couple of advantages, right?
So the first one is that it's a very staking business, right?
Which allows you to basically create some kind of barriers
of entry or switching costs for your clients,
and allows you to monetize your clients
more in the long term versus other services.
And at the same time, you're exactly right.
So there are certain services that are enabled
by custodians, right?
And those services are much easier to monetize
than the pure custody service.
If we think about staking,
is one of the most profitable activities in today's market,
and custodians really have the capability
of capturing most of the monetization opportunity.
- So let's talk about staking.
I mean, you know, we're seeing now
a rise of staking as a service, right?
Where a lot of custodians are offering the service,
even a lot of crypto exchanges are offering,
you know, staking services as well.
And I mean, for many holders of certain crypto assets,
whether it's Ethereum or other layer ones or layer twos,
staking is actually pretty good way
to get a yield on that asset.
What's your view on staking as a service?
Do you think in the next couple of years,
we're gonna see all the custodians offer staking services?
And how difficult you think that is
for a custodian to set that up?
All right, so staking is, I mean,
as of today in the blockchain space,
obviously proof of stake is the state of art, right?
So it is obvious that staking is kind of the,
this inflation protection mechanism, right?
Similar to the overnight rate that we have
in the traditional market, right?
So we'll, eventually we'll have a kind of a staking yield
that will be more or less aligned with the inflation
that the protocol offers.
So if the investor wants to protect himself against
the inflation of the protocol, staking is the solution.
So it is something that is here at the state
until proof of stake would be the state of the art
for blockchain protocols.
Now, since you mentioned exchanges,
I think that it's very important to do a clarification
between what staking is on an exchange platform,
a centralized exchange platform,
and what staking actually means for a custodian.
If you're staking your assets via a custodian,
it is very likely that you have your own segregated wallet.
And it is very likely that the custodian
is signing a staking transaction
to allow you to delegate your funds to a node,
a validator node in that specific blockchain protocol.
This is exactly what staking is about.
Whatever exchanges are offering today in the market
is not staking, right?
Exchanges actually an anomaly in the blockchain market.
An anomaly that eventually will have to be sorted out or solved.
Yeah, so what exchanges offer is an omnibus account
where all clients funds are commingled.
And when you press that button of staking,
you're not actually staking.
You're transferring your assets,
the ownership to the exchange
by different types of contracts.
For example, you're lending the funds to them.
You're becoming an unsecured creditor to the exchange.
Then the exchange would take these funds
and that would decide what to do with them.
They might decide to state them.
They might decide not to state them.
They might decide to use them for different purposes
as we have seen in a number of failures or platforms.
So this is not staking.
At best, is a collective investment scheme
and some regulators are actually correct in flagging
that that kind of activity should be a regulated activity.
So blockchain, to conclude blockchain has given us
very important tools of creating wallets
or segregating assets of tracking activities
and movement of funds and staking is a non-chain activity.
So as a non-chain activity,
it should be enabled in the correct way
with segregated wallets
as it's been designed in all the blockchain protocols.
And in this kind of shape and form,
I think it is here to stay
until we have proof of stake as the state of the art.
- It's a very interesting point, by the way,
you mentioned on whether exchanges offering staking services
could be considered a collective investment scheme, right?
I mean, if as a user, you're getting your, let's say,
eat to a certain exchange
who's then obviously just giving you the yield back,
there's an argument to be done that was actually,
that's a mutual fund, it's a collective investment scheme,
unlike if it's really happening on chain transaction
where there is purely the service.
I think this is the argument
where in some of the recent ACC cases,
between certain exchanges, we won't name them here,
but this was the legal argument that was made
from their general councils at how the setup was different.
But I think it's a very important point
you mentioned on that side, Alessio.
I just wanna come back on the point
of building a custodian, right?
So obviously, we discussed that.
Many believe that custody could be commoditized
at one point in the future.
What is the most difficult part
in building a custody business?
What is the biggest challenge that you didn't anticipate
when you start building Hex Trust
that you think a lot of the traditional banks
and other players are kind of underestimating
as they get into their custody business setup journey?
- All right.
I think there is one, to answer your question,
I'll mention two at least, yeah?
So there's one general aspect of custody,
which I think is the most important one,
and it's security, right?
As a custodian, we only have one shot, right?
The first time that we fail to provide security
to our clients and we lose clients assets, we're done, right?
So that is the core aspect and that is where
the majority of our attention, of our focus
should actually be, right?
And it's something that people take for granted, right?
But it cannot be taken for granted
because we have a number of people
that are investing a lot of money
to find possible ways of bridging into our systems
to take clients assets.
So this will always be the most important thing for us
to offer the highest possible level of security.
Now, in terms of the biggest challenge after security,
it's actually something that, to be honest,
I was not even expecting in 2017
when we were setting up the company.
The market, as I was mentioning, was very different.
We probably didn't even have proof of stake
as kind of something that was really
having traction in the market.
The most challenging thing is that the technology
that we need to provide is changing every day.
The use case is the business models
that we need to support today did not exist before.
So as of today, I'll give you some examples.
Back in 2018, a couple of blockchains
where the most important blockchains,
today, we need to support 30, 40 different protocols.
On every single protocol,
we have a lot of different token standards.
It's not just ERC 20, but we need to support ERC 20,
ERC 7 to 1, ERC 1155.
And now new standards that are coming to the market,
security, token type of standards.
And this is not just for Ethereum.
It can be for EVN compatible.
It could be for Cosmos based chains.
So it makes the complexity exponential.
Then you have bridges.
So tokens can exist on different blockchains,
so you need to bridge them seamlessly
from one blockchain to the other.
Then you have staking protocols,
and every staking protocol on every single blockchain protocol
functions in a completely different way.
And then now you have web three connectivity.
Who in 2018 was thinking about web three connectivity?
The possibility of interacting with a variety
of DeFi applications, of gaming applications,
of metaversus, et cetera,
and allow your users to connect the wallet
and claim tokens and being able to interact
to sign blind transactions, et cetera, in a secure way.
All of this, just to conclude, back in 2018,
the standard was kind of cold wallets,
the state of the art.
Nowadays, it doesn't work anymore.
You cannot connect your cold wallet to Uniswap
and Sime a transaction on time, right?
So you need to provide the highest level of security,
but you need to provide it in a very quickly,
in a very quick way, very efficient,
and across different jurisdictions in a 24 by 7 way.
So this is a very, very complex problem for custodians.
And I want to highlight,
I don't think we are at this stage
where the service is commoditized at all, yeah?
Lastly, just to conclude,
probably we'll talk about it more later,
but there's the whole elephant in the room of regulation.
Every single country has a different framework
and regulation as custodians.
We need to support global clients.
So we need to understand how to comply with regulations
across all the jurisdictions where we operate
and where our clients operate.
- So you raised so many good points, Alessio.
I think we know whenever I had discussions
with bank CEOs or boards,
or often they tell me,
"Yeah, we're thinking of getting a custody."
But some of the elements you mentioned on security,
the fashion and technology,
these are as you know very well,
as somebody who's worked in traditional finance
for many years,
it's very difficult for large financial institutions
to get into, right?
So often this is why many of them are just investing
or they look acquiring companies,
probably like yours,
just to actually be able to offer the service
and instead of them trying to build it, right?
So that's a very, very interesting point of view there.
- And I think, I mean,
since you mentioned these institutions
and banks in particular, right?
So we work with so many banks
to try to understand what kind of offering
they wanted to bring to the market.
But I mean, speed,
the speed of change is really critical in the space.
Banks do RFIs, RFPs.
The average duration of this process is probably two years.
By the time they have made a decision
on how to go to market,
basically they have probably approved,
okay, to do Bitcoin and Ethereum.
And in the meantime, the last 24 months,
the whole market has changed.
And whatever they have approved
is not relevant anymore to enable a profitable
or competitive business model.
So the speed at which traditional financial institutions
and banks in particular operate
is not aligned with what's happening in the market.
So either, I think either the only ones
that were able to go to market with something
are the ones that really partnered up with providers
or custodians institutions in the blockchain space
that are really expert in the space
and they can move at the right speed.
- Yeah, I agree.
I think that's gonna be one of the biggest challenges
for any of the trad five firms
trying to enter the market for sure.
You mentioned something, Alexia, that I wanna touch upon.
Obviously, as a custodian,
they're offering services to a global client base.
Regulation is a big topic, right?
And you mentioned obviously you're active at Hong Kong
and Dubai and Italy, France and Obama's other places.
I mean, what you're finding is the biggest challenge
in operating in a global environment
with different regulators,
especially when it comes from a custody perspective.
Is that you believe a molt
that gives you an advantage of others
can not enter as easily?
Is it good because it gives a customer protection
or it just becomes too confusing
and basically nobody's really benefiting from it.
- All right, so regulations are unfortunately
still very different across different countries.
Even tier one markets,
they still have regulations that differ from each other
quite a bit, right?
Just to give you some examples, right?
So we have a, I think a regulation in the UAE
in Dubai in particular, which is quite advanced, right?
And defines very well the role of a custodian, right?
Versus the role of other intermediaries.
At the same time in Hong Kong,
we know very well that we have a new framework,
a regulation that only covers exchanges, right?
And puts together the activity of a custodian
only within the regulatory framework of exchanges.
So we have, in other jurisdictions,
custodians are not even regulated, right?
But they only have to comply with basic AML-CTF rules, right?
So it is very different every jurisdiction
and it makes our job quite difficult.
However, I think there is a common denominator
of rules that I would say apply across all jurisdictions,
a basic set of standards and best practices
that we believe that eventually will apply
across all relevant jurisdictions where we want to operate.
And we try to kind of use this common denominator
across all jurisdictions and to be as compliant as possible.
This sometimes doesn't make us competitive enough
in certain jurisdictions,
but I think it's a trade-off that we have to take
if we really want to be competitive more in the long term
rather than tactically.
- Yeah, you mentioned Hong Kong regulations, actually,
as a company that was Hong Kong native
and obviously I've known you for many years
in Hong Kong as well, what do you think Hong Kong obviously
was a very big crypto hub back in the day.
It had a little more difficult times
and now it's looking like it's making a comeback.
What is your view on the rebirth of the Hong Kong
crypto ecosystem, particularly in contrast
with other up-and-coming jurisdictions like Dubai
and some European jurisdictions as well?
- Yeah, so I think Hong Kong is obviously
a great place to be for a financial business
in the blockchain space.
It's a great place to be because it's one
of the largest financial centers in the world.
It's a hub of innovation.
Shenzhen is right across the border,
so we have access to lots of big talent pool, et cetera.
There's also a lot of capital, which really helps
in terms of when you want to provide financial services
or becoming a relevant player in the space.
It gives you access to huge markets,
for example, to the mainland market,
as well as the, I would say, the broader Asian market.
The Hong Kong in theory is one of the best places to be
to start at least a wholesale blockchain business
as well as retail if you have access to certain markets.
Now, what happened is that lots of businesses
were coming to Hong Kong, especially in the ICO boom phase
and the regulator tried to reduce the risk
for retail investors by bamming these type of activities
and becoming a little bit more reluctant
to accept the companies to operate
in a completely unregulated environment.
Lots of businesses left Hong Kong to find better places.
And when I say better, it's places where they could operate
without too much supervision on one side
and on the other side, having clearer rules
which did not exist in Hong Kong.
Why they come back?
So now Hong Kong for whatever reason has decided
to become a global hub for blockchain
and crypto businesses.
This means that the government together with the regulators
are putting in place rules and regulations
that allow companies to come back,
to register themselves and to operate legally
under certain regulatory frameworks, right?
And this is important because it gives you access
to one of the, I would say top tier regulatory licenses, right?
Recognized in top tier jurisdictions
and current jurisdictions, as well as it gives you access
to the traditional finance rails, right?
Once you have the right licensing Hong Kong,
you'll be able to open bank accounts with banks
and do business with traditional financial institutions.
As a manager, suspension funds, institutional brokers, et cetera.
So this is a huge opportunity, right?
Hong Kong saw that other jurisdictions
that were slowing down and they saw the opportunity
to actually take back the business,
to put in place a regulation and kind of step
onto the stage and become the main player in Asia.
I think this is happening.
The first step, what they did was to regulate exchanges.
In my personal opinion, they could have done more,
they could have done better
and regulate other types of intermediaries.
But at the end of the day, it's a first step,
more rules will come and other types of business
that will be able to regulate themselves
and to get a proper licensing on-call
and operate that business from here.
It's a good first step
and we'll see more and more businesses coming here.
I think as of today, in kind of Asia, Middle East,
the only other place that is as attractive
as Hong Kong was probably Dubai.
So we, since Hexra says lies in both jurisdictions,
I think we're really in a good place
to operate our business.
- Yeah, it's interesting as well.
I think a lot of people that we speak to on the show,
other places, it's always now like Hong Kong
and Dubai coming up in the conversation.
Abu Dhabi, in certain cases as well.
And then it's actually France, which is like, again,
coming, making come back in a way
on that perspective as well.
- And we just got the license last week, so.
- Here we go, congratulations on that as well.
Let's show, I want to ask one last question.
We're already out of time.
I want to make sure I ask one more question on
when it comes to this obviously post FTX,
a lot of conversations around self custody, right?
And as a custodian,
how do you see the future of the custody ecosystem?
Will it be a place where centralized players
will have a dominant role?
Will it be one where self custody will have a dominant role
or be a hybrid one or a mix of all of these?
- I think this is the hardest question.
Is there a $1 million question?
What I see is that the regulated market
will have regulated custodians, right?
And these regulated custodians
that will have to register themselves as VASPs,
that will have to comply with travel rule, et cetera.
Once you comply with travel rule,
kind of all the unregulated wallets and everything,
we'll face some difficulties in interacting
with the regulated business.
So I think in the short term,
we'll see this kind of dichotomy
between regulated businesses
and the more unregulated self custody type of activities.
In terms of how the world will evolve
more in the medium to long term,
I think two things will have to coexist.
And we will have tools to make sure
that the two things can actually converge
and interact with each other in a legal way.
What we can do from a custody perspective
is to be adding one another layer of complexity
is to basically be as flexible as possible.
So as a custody platform,
as of today, we only allow custodial wallets.
By the end of the year,
we'll be able to provide our clients
with the ability to set up custodial wallets,
where we are in full control of prior keys,
as well as self custodial wallets,
where clients will operate wallets via our platform,
but where they control the prior keys of the wallet,
as well as share custody models,
which is a hybrid model where the prior key
is basically controlled in part by the custodian
and in part by the client itself.
So for us, it's basically enabling
as many business models as possible
to make sure that our clients
can find the right solution for their business.
- Excellent.
Well, last year, we're gonna go to our fire round of question
to finish off the show.
My bell is with me today.
So I'm gonna ask you quick questions
that I need a one or two word answer, basically.
You know, so it'll be very quick on that perspective
and we'll have some fun.
Are you ready?
- I'm ready.
- Let's kick it off.
Alessio, you live in Hong Kong.
What is your favorite thing to do when you're in Hong Kong?
- Play tennis.
- Oh, really? Here we go.
Favorite tennis player of all time?
- Roger Federer.
- Difficult to disagree with that.
Alessio, you're Italian.
What is your favorite thing to do
when you're back in Italy?
- Eat pasta. (laughs)
And pizza.
- What is the one, your favorite Italian restaurant
outside of Italy?
Your favorite Italian restaurant
that you recommend for people outside of Italy?
- There's a very good pizza place here in Hong Kong called Fyada.
- Yeah, of course.
Well, here you go.
Free advertisement for Fyada.
You know, you're a wine guy, of course.
What is your favorite type of wine
that I think people underrate and do not give enough credit?
- Drentodok, Italian kind of champagne method,
sparkling wine from the north of Italy.
- Here we go.
My God, the patriotism there.
What is the downside of having a wife that is a sommelier?
- Too much drinking.
(laughing)
- Let's come back to work.
What is the one skill you think is essential
for any entrepreneur in crypto?
- Persistence across the world cycles.
- Exactly.
What is the one advice you give to anyone
who wants to get into crypto?
The one advice you give to anyone
Thank you twice.
- Thank you twice.
(laughing)
I love it.
Your nephew comes to you and says
he wants to get into the crypto,
become a crypto entrepreneur.
He's debating between a couple of options
to get some experience, working in investment banking,
working at a regulator, working consulting,
or just going and doing his startup.
What do you recommend?
- Do your own startup.
- Yeah, it was that.
- Fail.
- And then work for the regulator.
(laughing)
- I love it.
Now, let's go.
We have to finish off on the show today.
Alesso Quaglini, the CEO and co-founder Hex Trust.
Alessio, if you could have lunch or dinner
with one person dead or alive.
Lunch or dinner with one person dead or alive.
Who would you have lunch or dinner with?
- My wife.
- What a romantic man.
That's Italian Simon.
(laughing)
- Here we go.
The Somelier wife was gonna get to treat you
on your birthday today.
Well, Alessio, it was a pleasure having you
with the on the show today.
How can people find out more about you
or learn more about Hex Trust?
- Well, I mean, hextrust.com is our website.
Most of the information is there.
And my telegram on chain Panini.
So very easy to remember.
Feel free to contact me.
- On chain Panini.
- Again, the stereotypical Italian does it again.
So Alessio, thanks for being with us on your birthday.
Thank you everybody who was on the show today.
I hope you found the show useful.
If you found it again,
please give us a five star rating.
It really helps and more people
discovering the show from that perspective.
Thank you very much, everybody.
And see you all next time for another episode
of the Future of Money Podcast.
See you guys also.
(upbeat music)